DR REBECCA MCELROY

ASTROPHYSICIST & DATA SCIENTIST

CONTACT

0401 121 826

r.mcelroy@uq.edu.au

rebeccamcelroy.github.io

Brisbane, Australia

SKILLS

Problem solving

Data analysis and visualisation

Communication and public speaking

Team leadership

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Physics) University of Sydney

2014-2017

CITIZENSHIP & LANGUAGES

Australian & British citizen

Native English, Intermediate French & German

REFERENCES

Prof Tamara Davis

+61 7 336 53433

tamarad@physics.uq.edu.au

Prof Scott Croom

+61 2 9036 5311

scott.croom@sydney.edu.au

PROFILE

I am a passionate research scientist with 10 years experience in scientific data analysis and problem solving. I am an expert in analysing noisy data in tabular, time-series, and imaging formats, using Python and R.

I am a clear and dynamic communicator, experienced in presenting technical projects to both experts and non-experts.

I am looking for a rewarding position in which I can use my advanced technical skills beyond research.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow

The University of Queensland

2021- present

- I am an independent research fellow in the School of Mathematics and Physics.
- I lead a team of thirty international scientists in a collaboration using data from ground and space-based telescopes to understand nearby galaxies.
- I teach postgraduate level Astrophysics and supervise students in research projects.

Postdoctoral Researcher

The University of Sydney

2020-2021

- Coordinating undergraduate Astronomy courses which includes: lecturing, tutoring, exam creation and marking.
- · Research as part of a team

Postdoctoral Researcher

Max Planck Institute for Astronomy

2017-2020

 Data processing, analysis, and verification for a large survey using Python and bash.

Equal Opportunity Officer

Max Planck Institute for Astronomy

2017-2020

- · Workshop and lecture organisation
- · Hiring oversight
- Conflict resolution and mediation